Is it really wise for Shockwave to spawn an army of beasts
here in this laboratory, or within any part of this warship?
I mean, not even the lone beast we had was compact enough
to stroll these corridors without tearing them asunder.
Which reminds me, I am so very sorry for your loss.
I was referring to my offsite laboratory,
which we have erected expressly for the cloning procedures.
You think of everything, don't you?
We are under attack.
Autobots?
Illogical.
Though there appears to be an enormous mass upon the upper hull.
How did it find us?
Predacons possess precise homing instincts.
And astonishing resilience.
Starscream, assume command of my beast.
Me, master?
I... I mean, I wouldn't dream of seizing such an honor from its very creator.
Military command of the Predacon is most logical,
since my services are required elsewhere.
All right, Beast Hunters. According to our intel,
the Decepticons should be excavating for Predacon bones directly beneath us.
On it, chief.
Does Wheeljack not comprehend the chain of command?
I didn't authorize him to advance without proper cover.
Yeah... I'm sure Jackie's just trying to prove himself now that you and he are serving together again, sir.
Yee-ha!
Jackie, wait up.
Ultra Magnus wants us...
Blah, blah, blah.
Shh! Shh!
Wrecker fact number 17:
"Guards never look up."
Scrap.
That's why we wait for cover.
Ah, bolts.
Uh...
Forgot you were in there, kid.
At least I didn't heave on any floormats this time.
You miserable beast. I am your commanding officer,
and I order you to crawl into your kennel, now!
I said go, already!
Ahh!
And what could have possibly compelled you to bring the nativ?
Yo.
Can I come with?
Why not?
Are your circuits impaired, soldier?
Prime told you to lead the Wreckers on this one.
I assumed he meant all of 'em.
Are you mocking your commanding officer?
Wouldn't think of it, sir.
The kid's a full-blown Wrecker. Isn't that right, Bulkhead?
Well...
Look. She may be small, but she saved my tailpipe.
Snuffed an Insecticon all on her own.
Outside standard protocol, no doubt.
The point is, I can handle myself, sir.
Miko has been through worse,
and we've drawn out the enemy and cleared passage.
Okay, now in you go.
Do your worst. The Apex armor is virtually...
Ahh! Oh, oh! No! Ahh! Release me!
Starscream, are you with the beast?
Yes, master.
We've been reviewing attack maneuvers. He's doing quite well.
One of the excavation teams has failed to report in.
I shall assemble my seeker armada immediately and...
I would prefer that you lead our newly-returned asset on this mission,
so that we may see if our Predacon is as adept at fetching bones as it is hunting Autobots.
Is this it?
No. That is a rock.
Heh. Just like old times, huh, Jackie?
Except back then, I didn't need permission to pick my partners.
Come on, we're all on the same team.
Hey, Beast Hunters, right?
During all those cycles it took me to travel to Earth,
all I could think about was getting our band of brothers back together.
But this isn't the lineup I had in mind.
You did the smart thin, Bulk, leaving the Wreckers when you did.
While we were still bringing our A-game, before the rust set in.
Wait, I thought Wheeljack was the one who left the Wreckers.
Jackie basically deserted once the Wreckers fell under Ultra Magnus' command.
I transferred out before that, to join up with Optimus in the battle of Thunderhead Pass.
Sometimes I think Jackie feels like I deserted him.
You don't wanna be the one who breaks up the band, Bulk.
Oh!
What was that?
Whatever it is, it's big.
And it's coming fast.
The Predacon. Let's roll.
It's back?
Accelerate!
That rock won't hold it forever. We need to contact base and request reinforcements.
Wreckers don't call for backup.
What Jackie means is, we can't get a comm-link signal this far underground.
Miko, I have to get you out of here. Gonna need you to climb.
No way. I wanna help.
And you will.
Your mission: Reach my ship so you can contact Optimus Prime.
Yes, sir.
Not sure I like the sound of that.
So, uh...
We make our stand... here and now.
Given that this ship is currently unoccupied,
it would seem the Autobots did stumble upon our little mining operation.
No worries.
My Predacon is no doubt dismantling the interlopers as we speak.
It was a challenge, but I managed to tame the savage beast.
Taught it to heed my every command.
Come on, come on.
You're not wearing the armor to protect yourself from it?
From my beloved pet? Of course not.
In fact, it's getting rather warm in here.
Ah, ventilation.
Open fire!
Whoa!
No you don't.
Hey, hot-head!
Oh, scrap.
Ooh, that'll do some damage.
Miko, is it?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Were you trying to reach this ship? To call for help, perhaps?
What's the matter, 'Screamy? Can't pick on someone your own size?
What do you know, it does fetch.
Scrap.
Well, that didn't go exacty as planned.
That's because any first-cycle Cadet knows better than to detonate a grenade in a confined space.
Even if I intended the "confined space" to be the belly of the beast?
Uh, sir...
Your actions continue to be just one step removed from getting us all scrapped.
With all due respect, sir,
the Predacon's loose and Miko's out there alone.
Permission to provide cover, sir?
Go ahead, make a wreck of her, as you no doubt did the Wreckers.
Starscream, status report.
Master. We have secured the bone, and our Predacon is dealing with the Autobots' pet human as we speak.
On my command, of course.
I will not risk losing a precious commodity to your arrogance.
I'll tear you apart!
Have the beast return with my prize, immediately!
You can stay behind and finish the Autobots.
Yes, master.
Assuming I can coerce the brainless brute into...
But, you never obey my commands!
You heard our Master. We must locate the Autobots.
As soon as I retrieve what belongs to me.
Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk... Even the strongest armor can't protect the weakest of creatures.
Protected you, didn't it?
Who's wrecking who now?
Miko?
Perhaps you weren't wrong about the human after all.
You do know that I vanquished Cliffjumper, don't you?
Big whoop.
I snuffed Hardshell.
Ah! Retreat.
Aw.
They got away with the bone.
Hey, you brought your A-game, kid,
like a true Wrecker.
And I wanna remember us just like this...
before the rust sets in.
What? Where's Wheeljack going?
Solo.
Again?
Jackie just broke up the band.